Portfolio: cslyons1.github.io/csl.github.io · LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/cody-lyons

OBJECTIVE

Seeking to apply a decade of project management background, high-level communication skills, collaborative leadership approaches, and experience working in generative AI to effectively manage teams in pursuit of progressing the capabilities of advanced AI models.

WORK EXPERIENCE

xAI Oct. 2024 – Current

Al Tutor (Data Trainer)

Remote

- Developed, deployed, and continually maintain a division-wide project management communications system, keeping communications and project documentation for highly dynamic multimodal project teams efficient and cohesive while allowing five Team Leads to manage the workflows of more than 100 AI Data Trainers across seven projects simultaneously
- Created and refined our multimodal division onboarding procedures resulting in a 50% reduction in project onboarding time for new AI Data Trainers
- Manage and drive dynamic multimodal team workflows, delegating responsibility to ensure project milestones are met
- Develop QA parameters of multimodal projects ensuring generative AI models are being trained in line with Researcher and Project Lead's project parameters
- Create and implement standard operating procedures for training generative AI models

Regency Commercial Construction

Dec. 2019 - Jan. 2023

Assistant Project Manager

Beltsville, MD

Executed project management duties on concurrent, large-scale projects within diverse teams of stakeholders including:

- Managed all aspects of multiple concurrent, dynamic projects, monitoring multi-faceted project data and actively adjusting schedules, budgets, and scopes of work to ensure milestones were met, resulting in early project turnover and increased profits
- Employed version control practices to develop, organize, and distribute project information to project teams
- Served as liaison between engineers, architects, stakeholders and subcontractors, maintaining communication between all parties, and facilitating positive working relationships that resulted in return work

ADP Consultants Feb. 2019 – Dec. 2019

Assistant Project Manager

Capitol Heights, MD

Performed project management duties on large-scale government projects and assisted company owner in the following:

- Tracked key project milestones and prepared status update documentation for presentation to stakeholders
- Created and reviewed project-specific documents for compliance with contract documents
- Facilitated communication with project stakeholders and maintained positive working relationships

Clark Concrete Contractors Sept. 2016 – Aug. 2018

Quality Control Engineer

Bethesda, MD

Collaborated with government agency stakeholders to manage project-specific quality control procedures including:

- Implemented project-specific document version control and access structures across large-scale, dynamic projects to regulate, update, and distribute project documents between stakeholders and project teams
- Developed and implemented quality control plans and presented related project data reports to stakeholders
- Reviewed and issued contract document submissions for approval

Hillis-Carnes Engineering Associates

Jul. 2008 - Sept. 2016

Engineering Technician

Annapolis Junction, MD

- Developed detailed reports documenting operations, project and material-related issues, and solution proposals
- Created and implemented quality control procedures on large-scale projects
- Upheld communication between stakeholders, contractors, and third-party consultants

SKILLS

Project Management, Effective Communication, Data Analysis, Data Visualization, Creative Problem Solving, Python

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATION

The Pennsylvania State University

Bachelor of Science, Integrated Social Sciences

Google Data Analytics

Professional Certificate in Data Analytics from Google